Now, you know how to get information from
现在你知道如何从 Web 应用后端获取信息传送给前端
but what we really want is to pass the information
但我们真正想要从后端传递到前端的是可视化信息
I've written some code that sets up
我写了一些代码
a Plotly visualization on the back end and sends that information to the front end.
在后端设置 Plotly 可视化 并将该信息发送到前端
Then the front and plots the visualization.
然后在前端绘制可视化
I'm going to walk you through this code and then I'll provide
我将引导你浏览这些代码 然后提供
similar code as part of an exercise so that you can become familiar with it.
类似代码作为练习的一部分 方便你熟悉
So, what has changed?
那么有哪些变化?
First, I've pip installed Plotly into my workspace using pip install Plotly.
首先 使用 pip install plotly 将 Plotly 安装到我的 workspace
If I do that here in the terminal,
如果我现在在终端操作
nothing's going to actually happen because I've already installed it.
什么都不会发生 因为我已经安装好了
You see here that it says requirement already satisfied.
这里看到终端显示说需求已经满足了
In the roots.py file,
在 routes.py 文件中
I'm importing the Plotly library,
我导入了 plotly 库
the json library, and graph objects from Plotly.
json 库和 plotly 库中的 graph_objs
Then, I'm getting the wrangle data by calling the data wrangling function,
然后 我通过调用 data_wrangling 函数来获取整理后的数据
and I'm printing out the first tuple so that you can see what the data looks like.
我打印出第一个元组 可以看到数据的样子
In this visualization, I'm going to visualize the first tuple for now.
在这个可视化中 我暂时只绘制第一个元组的数据
That's why in the country variable,
这就是为什么在 country 变量中
I've only grab the first tuples country value,
我只取了第一个元组的 country 值
and then the x values and the y values of the first tuple.
然后是第一个元组的 x 值和 y 值
To remind you of what the data looks like,
为了让你了解现在数据的样子
I'm just going to run this new web app for a second,
我先运行一次这个新的 Web 应用
so that you can see the results in the terminal.
这样你就可以在终端看到结果
So, here it is,
在这里
United States 1990 to 2015,
美国 1990 年至 2015 年
then the y-values are 24.7 and 18.383.
y 值是 24.7 和 18.383
Hopefully, the code that comes next looks somewhat familiar,
希望接下来的代码你能觉得眼熟
because it's very, very similar to the JavaScript code for plotting with Plotly.
因为它与绘制 Plotly 的 JavaScript 代码非常非常相似
Inside this graph one variable,
在这个 graph_one 变量中
I'm preparing a line chart using the x values,
我准备绘制一个折线图
y values, and country name.
使用 x 值 y 值和国家 name
The visualization has to be in a list,
可视化必须在列表中
which is why have square brackets around this go.scatter syntax.
这就是在这个 go.Scatter 语法周围有方括号的原因
How, you might ask,
你可能会问
did I figure out the syntax for all of this?
我该如何找到所有这些语法?
Well, I read through Plotly's Python library documentation.
答案是 通读 Plotly 的 Python 库文档
Next, comes the layout,
接下来到布局部分
which has to be in a dictionary.
layout 必须在字典中
The syntax might be a little bit confusing but this is just a dictionary of dictionaries.
语法可能有点令人困惑 这是一个字典组成的字典
Again, I figured this out through reading the Plotly documentation.
我这次也是通过阅读 Plotly 文档来解决这个问题的
The next part of the code is setting things up
代码的下一部分是
for when there are multiple visualizations.
当有多个可视化时的设置
Although for now, there is only one visualization,
虽然目前只有一个可视化
I'll get to multiple visualizations a little later.
稍后我会进行多个可视化的绘制
The IDs variable will be a list,
ids 变量是一个列表
containing distinct ids for each plot like;
包含每个图表的不同 id
figure zero, figure one,
比如 figure-0 figure-1 等等
et cetera, and then figure Json converts the dictionary is holding
然后 figuresJSON 将存有可视化信息的字典
the visualizations into a form that Plotly can interpret in the JavaScript front-end.
转换为 Plotly 可以在 JavaScript 前端解释的形式
Next, I send the list of IDs and
接下来 我在 render_template 方法中传入
the figure's Json variables to the front and in the render template method.
ids 列表和 figuresJSON 变量 将其发送到前端
So, let's look at the index.html file for the front end.
那么 我们来看一下前端的 index.html 文件
Here, I've put a link to the JavaScript Plotly library in line six,
这里 我在第六行中添加了一个指向 JavaScript Plotly 库的链接
and I've also printed out the IDs variable and figures Json variables in paragraphs,
我还在段落中打印出了 ids 变量和 figuresJSON 变量
so that you can see what their values look like.
这样你就可以看到它们的值
That's going to be printed out to the front end.
这些将在前端打印出来
Do you remember before when you use Plotly and
还记得之前使用 Plotly 和
JavaScript and you created divs for each plot?
JavaScript 的时候 为每个图表创建了 div 吗?
That's what I'm doing here in line 14,
这就是我在第 14 行所做的事情
by taking the first ID in the IDs list.
获取了 ids 列表中的第一个 id 作为 div 的 id
If I had more plots,
如果我有更多的图表
I need to make more divs for the other IDs like;
我需要为其他 id 制作更多的 div
id bracket one, bracket two, etcetera.
ids[1] ids[2] 等等
Finally, the JavaScript code below uses
最后 下面的 JavaScript 代码使用
the figures Json variables and ids from the front end,
来自前端的 figuresJSON 变量和 ids
and then plots each visualization one at a time,
一次绘制一个可视化
iterating through the IDs, data, and layouts.
遍历 ids data 和 layout
But for now, I only have one visualization.
但就目前而言 我只有一个可视化
This safe word here is an escape filter.
这里的 safe 单词是一种 escape 过滤器
Escaping just make sure that if the figures or ID variables use
escape 过滤器只是确保如果 figures 或 ids 变量使用
any HTML special characters like the greater than or less than brackets,
任何 HTML 特殊字符 如大于号或小于号
these get interpreted correctly.
这些字符能够被正确解释
I'm going to give you all of this code so you don't have to rewrite this.
我将为你提供所有这些代码 因此你无需重写
All you'll need to do is make a div for each visualization with the correct ID,
你需要做的就是使用正确的 id 为每个可视化创建一个 div
and place the div where you want the visualization to appear.
并将 div 放在要显示可视化的位置
Let's see what the front end looks like.
让我们看看前端的样子
So, this is the index.html page,
这是 index.html 页面
and then this is the figure ID,
这里是图表 id
and then this is the value that was in figures Json, and then here's the plot.
这是 figuresJSON 中的值 然后这是图表
So it worked. So far,
所以代码成功了
the front end maybe isn't that well organized,
目前为止 也许前端还组织得不太好
and maybe it's not clear how to make multiple plots,
也许还不清楚如何绘制多个图表
or to plot multiple lines on one plot but that's what I'm going to show you next.
或者如何在一个图表上绘制多条折线 但这就是我接下来要讲的